http://www.zonealarm.com/privacy

Save
Big Holiday Savings!
Privacy
This document was last updated May 2, 2018.
Zone Labs, L.L.C. (“ZoneAlarm”) is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains our
privacy
practices for our website, www.zonealarm.com on the World Wide Web (the “Site”), as well as for all
ZoneAlarm
products, Cloud and Internet-delivered services that may be accessed through the normal use of our products
(the
“Services”). You can travel through most of our Site without giving us any information about yourself. But
sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request. The following statement explains our
information-gathering and dissemination practices. Please read the complete ZoneAlarm Privacy Policy.
General Information
ZoneAlarm Capsule
What Information We Gather/Track
If You Opt to Receive Communications, How We Will Contact You
General Information
ZoneAlarm may periodically update this Privacy Policy. If so, ZoneAlarm will post the updated Privacy Policy
on
this Site. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified
in
your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. ZoneAlarm
encourages
you to review this Privacy Policy from time to time for any changes.
By using this Site or any products or services provided through the Site, or by downloading the ZoneAlarm
Capsule
application, you expressly consent to the use and disclosure of information as described in this Privacy
Policy.
IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH ANY OF THE TERMS BELOW, YOU SHOULD NOT USE THIS SITE OR THE PRODUCTS OR SERVICES
OFFERED
BY ZONEALARM AT THIS SITE.
Please note that the ZoneAlarm User Forum is covered by its own privacy policy, which is available for review
at
any time.
ZoneAlarm Capsule
This Privacy Policy also applies to users of the ZoneAlarm Capsule Cloud Application, platform and/or
services
(“ZoneAlarm Capsule”). ZoneAlarm may process and store application and customer data, for a period of up to
30
days, in the United States, in a country within the European Economic Area (EEA), in a country recognized by
the
EEA as providing adequate protection of personal data, or in any other country in which ZoneAlarm or its
agents
maintain facilities. By using the ZoneAlarm Capsule, you consent to this processing and storage of
application and
customer data.
All traffic to the Check Point Gateway is encrypted. In addition, the Check Point Cloud uses certain
physical,
managerial and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of information collected.
However,
Check Point Cloud cannot ensure or guarantee that the safeguards will be uninterrupted or effective, or that
any
information a user transmits to the Services will remain secure, and Users so transmit at their own risk.
Check
Point Cloud cannot guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, destroyed by
breach of
Check Point Cloud’s physical, technical or managerial safeguards.
ZoneAlarm Capsule and Check Point Cloud do not secure or protect your computer, laptop, smart phone or tablet
from viruses or malware. We recommend obtaining anti-virus/anti-malware solutions from ZoneAlarm or another
reputable supplier in order to also help secure your device.
ZoneAlarm Capsule will not be transferring your email addresses to any third party.
What Information We Gather/Track
You may decide whether to proceed with any activity that requests personally identifiable information. If you
do
not wish to provide the requested information, however, you may not be able to complete the transaction. We
do not
collect information from individuals under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, we ask that you do
not
submit any personally identifiable information through the Site. If we have specific knowledge that an
individual
under the age of 13 has submitted personally identifiable information to the Site, we will delete such
information
permanently and without notice.
Except as described below, ZoneAlarm will only disclose your personally identifiable information to third
parties
if acting under a good faith belief that such action is necessary (1) to conform to legal requirements; (2)
to
protect and defend the rights or property of ZoneAlarm; (3) to enforce the ZoneAlarm Terms of Service; or
(4) in
the event of a merger, acquisition or sale of all or substantially all ZoneAlarm’s assets relating to the
business
in connection with which the information was collected. ZoneAlarm collects personally identifiable
information
that can be divided into the following categories:
+ ZoneAlarm Product Registration Information
Some ZoneAlarm products ask you for certain personally identifiable information as part of
the
installation/registration process (including but not limited to your name, email address,
credit card
information and connection type and number of computers). Certain of this information is
necessary in
order to conclude the transaction, and for applicable products, to be eligible to receive
technical
support. If you provide us with personally identifiable information, and select the “Inform
me about
important updates and news” option on the purchase confirmation page or in the in the
“Registration
Information” section located in the “Configuration Panel” of the “Control Panel” in the
ZoneAlarm product,
we use this information to send you communications, including informative emails/newsletters
about
ZoneAlarm product upgrades, product updates, new products, and services, and to provide you
with special
offers that may be of interest to you, including paid advertisements from third parties. In
the event you
no longer wish to receive such information, you may choose to opt out of receiving further
communications
by complying with the procedures listed in the “Updating/Unsubscribing Your Email Address”
section of this
Privacy Policy. Except in the case of Partner Products (see below), ZoneAlarm keeps
personally
identifiable information collected in the course of installation/registration of ZoneAlarm’s
products
confidential and does not sell, trade, or exchange mailing lists with any organization.
+ Partner Product Purchases
Some products offered via the Site are third-party products (“Partner Products”) offered by
ZoneAlarm’s
partners (“ZoneAlarm Partners”). If you purchase Partner Products from this Site, ZoneAlarm
will ask you
to provide personally identifiable information as part of the installation/registration
process (including
but not limited to your name, email address and credit card information). You are required
to provide this
information in order to conclude the transaction. ZoneAlarm provides this information,
except credit card
information, to the applicable ZoneAlarm Partner to enable the applicable Partner to
register your
purchase and verify support eligibility. ZoneAlarm will require the applicable ZoneAlarm
Partner to use
your information only to verify support eligibility and, in the case of certain Partner
Products, to
provide you required updates. ZoneAlarm will not share this information with any other third
party.
+ Co-branded Pages
ZoneAlarm provides commerce functionality for selected partner companies who wish to offer
ZoneAlarm
products to their customers and/or users. If you come to the Site by accessing a link
provided by a
partner company, you will be informed that your information (not including credit card) will
be shared
with the partner company. You will have the option to “opt-out” of promotional
communications from both
ZoneAlarm and the partner company when you register your product.
+ Credit Card Information
If you use a credit card to purchase products via this Site, your name as it appears on the
credit card,
the credit card number, expiration date and billing address will be encrypted as it passes
over the
Internet. ZoneAlarm does not record or keep your credit card information for online
credit-card
transactions; rather such information is simply passed through to our contracted payment
processing
vendor. ZoneAlarm may access such information through the payment processing company, but
does not do so
except to process refunds or adjustments, or when annual renewal of subscription is elected,
and to the
extent necessary in the event of nonpayment or disputed payments, or as may be necessary for
ZoneAlarm’s
compliance, in ZoneAlarm’s discretion, with applicable law.
+ Technical Support
If you request technical support online, we will ask you for information necessary to
complete the
transaction such as your name, email address and information about your computer hardware,
software, and
the nature of the problem you are experiencing. In the course of providing support, your
data may be
transmitted to service providers that are under contract to ZoneAlarm and have agreed to
abide by the
provisions of this privacy policy. Such transmissions of your data are encrypted and
secure.
+ Volume Sales Form
If you request volume licensing information online, we will ask you for information necessary
to complete
the transaction such as company name, email address, needs assessment and your
organization’s primary
business activity.
+ Partner Application
If you request participation in the partner program online, we will ask you for information
necessary to
complete the transaction such as company name, email address, and company profile.
+ Analyzing Security Alerts, “SmartDefense Advisor”
When the ZoneAlarm product detects a security threat to your computer, you can click on the
“More
Information” button from the product dialog box. At that point, the product sends the
information about
the event and your computer to ZoneAlarm to be analyzed. ZoneAlarm will display in your
browser more
specific guidance about the security information.*
* – One year of updates and service access included with purchase of a ZoneAlarm product;
annual
subscriptions available for subsequent updates and service access.
+ Loss of Internet Connectivity During Use of ZoneAlarm Products
If you have installed certain ZoneAlarm products, in very rare instances you may lose
connectivity to the
Internet due to an error on your computer or a hacker threat. In this rare event, you will
receive
instructions from ZoneAlarm on how to regain connectivity to the Internet. You will be given
the
opportunity to submit an error report to ZoneAlarm for diagnostic purposes only. Your
decision to submit
an error report to ZoneAlarm is purely voluntary. If you do submit such an error report,
ZoneAlarm will
copy error logs from your computer for error diagnosis. Any personally identifiable
information contained
in such error logs is purely incidental, will not be otherwise used by ZoneAlarm or shared
with any third
parties, and will be permanently deleted from our systems upon completion of our
analysis.
+ Surveys
ZoneAlarm periodically requests information from users via surveys. Participation in these
surveys is
completely voluntary and you have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.
ZoneAlarm uses
both in-house and third-party Web-Based Interviewing Systems to compile the surveys.
Information requested
in the surveys may include broad demographic information (such as zip code, age level) for
aggregate use
and does not identify the user. No cookies are used. Survey information is not sold, shared,
or rented to
any third party, and is used internally solely by ZoneAlarm for purposes of improving the
use and
satisfaction of this Site, Services, and our products.
+ Affiliates
When a user or a company signs up to be a marketing program affiliate, they do so through a
third-party
provider of affiliate marketing programs. Such third-party provider does share personally
identifiable
information about affiliates with ZoneAlarm. This information is not sold, shared, or rented
to any third
party, and is used internally only to manage and maintain relationships with affiliates. The
ZoneAlarm
privacy policy governs the information that is collected on Element5 and this information
will be used in
accordance with the ZoneAlarm privacy policy.
+ Search
The web search services herein are provided by Microsoft Bing. As part of the search functionality, third parties may collect or receive information
(including, without limitation, IP addresses and search terms) and use that information to provide measurement services, search results and other
advertisements, including personalized and targeted search results and advertisements. For information on collection of data as part of the web search
services, please visit the end user privacy statements of CodeFuel and
Bing, both as updated from time to time and at any successor locations. “
If You Opt to Receive Communications, How We Will Contact You
Email
With your permission, ZoneAlarm will send you communications, including informative emails/newsletters about
product upgrades, product updates, new products, and services. These communications provide you with special
offers that may be of interest to you, and may include paid advertisements from third parties. ZoneAlarm
uses a
third-party provider of outbound email technology to send email from their servers on our behalf. The
provider
does not collect information about you but does collect requests to unsubscribe.
Special Offers
ZoneAlarm has relationships with business partners that provide a number of third-party products and
services.
With your permission, ZoneAlarm will notify you about special offers that may include links to third-party
products and services.
Site Functionality
CookiesPersistent “cookies” are small pieces of information that your browser stores on your
computer
on behalf of a Web site that you have visited. The Site does not use persistent cookies. In order to
complete
transactions on our site, we do use session cookies. These session cookies do not collect information about
you,
only about your browser session, and they are destroyed when you close your browser. No data is stored on
your
computer.
The use of third party cookies is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over
these
cookies.
Third parties may be placing and reading cookies on your browsers or using web beacons to collect information
in
the course of advertising being served.
Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)Our third party advertising partner employs a software technology
called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing
us
what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to
cookies,
and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a
user’s
computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at
the
end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally
identifiable information.
Log FilesWe (ZoneAlarm and/or our contracted web analytics provider(s)) do keep track of the
domains
from which you access our Site and Services on the World Wide Web, and may log IP addresses or other
identifiers
for statistical purposes. We do this to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use to identify
and
analyze trends and the results of our marketing efforts, to help diagnose problems with our servers and to
administer the Site and Services, and analyze users’ movements. We may periodically share aggregate
demographic
information with our business partners. IP addresses and other identifiers are not linked to personally
identifiable information.
Security of Your Information
All information gathered on the Site is stored and maintained in secure facilities. In addition, internal
security provides that this information is coded with restricted access, and our servers are kept in a
secure,
locked environment that limits access to authorized personnel only. All ZoneAlarm employees, and all
external
service providers who may process and/or store customer data, are briefed about the company’s privacy and
security
policies on a regular basis. The Site is regularly tested for security breaches to ensure that all
information
collected is secure from unauthorized viewing. Any service providers with whom ZoneAlarm contracts, and who
receive, store, or process personally identifiable customer data, have committed to abide by the provisions
of
this privacy policy. All transmissions of personally identifiable customer data are encrypted and
secure.
When you enter sensitive information (such as your credit card number) on our forms, we encrypt the
transmission
of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).
If you have any questions about the security at our Site, you can send an email to privacy_support@zonealarm.com.
Please note that this email address will reject messages with attachments of any kind.
Behavioral Targeting / Re-TargetingWe partner with a third party ad network to either display
advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies
and
Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web
sites
to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish not to have this information used
for
the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by
clicking here
Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic
ads.
ZoneAlarm Services
In the course of normal operation, ZoneAlarm security products may contact servers operated by, or under
contract
to, ZoneAlarm. These communications are for the purpose of providing more specific information about
security
threats, system configuration, and the presence or properties of software, as well as to allow ZoneAlarm to
aggregate data in the interest of improving our Services and products.
No personally identifiable information is gathered during interactions with ZoneAlarm Services. We may
aggregate
data in order to analyze geographic or other demographic patterns, and may make such aggregated data
available to
Partners. Such aggregations will not reveal personally identifiable information about particular users.
You may opt out of these communications with ZoneAlarm during the installation and registration process. If
you
opt out, no information will be sent to ZoneAlarm; however, this may diminish the advisory, diagnostic, or
other
content being served to you.
Links to 3rd Party SitesOur Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may
differ
from those of ZoneAlarm. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is
governed by
their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.
Social Media WidgetsOur Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button
and
Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may
collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature
to
function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly
on our
Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
Public ForumsOur Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be
aware
that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.
To
request removal of your personally identifiable information from our blog or community forum, contact us at
privacy_support@zonealarm.com. In some cases, we may not
be
able to remove your personally identifiable information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable
to do
so and why.
International Transfers of Personal Data
ZoneAlarm is a global business. Our customers and our operations are spread around the world. As a result we
collect and transfer Personal Data on a global basis. That means that we may transfer your Personal Data to
locations outside of your country.
Where we transfer your Personal Data to another country outside the EEA, we will ensure that it is protected
and
transferred in a manner consistent with legal requirements. In relation to data being transferred outside of
Europe, for example, this may be done in one of the following ways:
The country that we send the data to might be approved by the European Commission as offering an
adequate
level of protection for Personal Data (Israel is an approved country);
The recipient might have signed up to a contract based on “model contractual clauses” approved by the
European
Commission, obliging them to protect your Personal Data;
Where the recipient is located in the US, it might be a certified member of the EU-US Privacy Shield
scheme;
or
In other circumstances the law may permit us to otherwise transfer your Personal Data outside Europe.
You can obtain more details of the protection given to your Personal Data when it is transferred outside
Europe
(including a copy of the standard data protection clauses which we have entered into with recipients of your
Personal Data) by contacting us as described in the section titled “Questions and Concerns” below.
How We Safeguard Your InformationWe have extensive controls in place to maintain the security of
our
information and information systems. Client files are protected with safeguards according to the sensitivity
of
the relevant information. Appropriate controls (such as restricted access) are placed on our computer
systems.
Physical access to areas where Personal Data is gathered, processed or stored is limited to authorised
employees.
As a condition of employment, ZoneAlarm employees are required to follow all applicable laws and regulations,
including in relation to data protection law. Access to sensitive Personal Data is limited to those
employees who
need to it to perform their roles. Unauthorised use or disclosure of confidential client information by a
ZoneAlarm employee is prohibited and may result in disciplinary measures.
When you contact a ZoneAlarm employee about your file, you may be asked for some Personal Data. This type of
safeguard is designed to ensure that only you, or someone authorised by you, has access to your file.
How Long We Keep Your Personal DataHow long we will hold your Personal Data for will vary and will
be
determined by the following criteria:
The purpose for which we are using it – ZoneAlarm will need to keep the data for as long as is necessary
for
that purpose; and
Legal obligations – laws or regulation may set a minimum period for which we have to keep your Personal
Data.
Your RightsIn all the above cases in which we collect, use or store your Personal Data, you may
have
the following rights and, in most cases, you can exercise them free of charge. These rights include:
the right to obtain information regarding the processing of your Personal Data and access to the
Personal Data
which we hold about you;
the right to withdraw your consent to the processing of your Personal Data at any time. Please note,
however,
that we may still be entitled to process your Personal Data if we have another legitimate reason for
doing so.
For example, we may need to retain Personal Data to comply with a legal obligation;
in some circumstances, the right to receive some Personal Data in a structured, commonly used and
machine-readable format and/or request that we transmit those data to a third party where this is
technically
feasible. Please note that this right only applies to Personal Data which you have provided directly to
ZoneAlarm;
the right to request that we rectify your Personal Data if it is inaccurate or incomplete;
the right to request that we erase your Personal Data in certain circumstances. Please note that there
may be
circumstances where you ask us to erase your Personal Data but we are legally entitled to retain it;
the right to request that we restrict our processing of your Personal Data in certain circumstances.
Again,
there may be circumstances where you ask us to restrict our processing of your Personal Data but we are
legally
entitled to refuse that request; and
the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant data protection regulator if you think that any of your
rights have been infringed by us.
You can exercise your rights by contacting us using the details listed in the section titled “Questions and
Concerns” below.
Designated RepresentativeZoneAlarm’s designated representative may be contacted using the
following
contact information:
UNITED STATES
Zone Labs, L.L.C.
959 Skyway Road, Suite 300
San Carlos, CA 94070
privacy_support@zonealarm.com
EU
Zone Labs, L.L.C.
Zeppelinstraße 1,
85399
Hallbergmoos,
Germany.
privacy_support@zonealarm.com
Questions and Concerns
If you have any questions or concerns about ZoneAlarm’s handling of your Personal Data, or about this
Policy,
please contact our Privacy Officer using the following contact information:
Zone Labs, L.L.C.
959 Skyway Road, Suite 300
San Carlos, CA 94070
privacy_support@zonealarm.com
We are usually able to resolve privacy questions or concerns promptly and effectively. If you are not
satisfied
with the response you receive from our Privacy Officer, you may escalate concerns to the applicable privacy
regulator in your jurisdiction. Upon request, ZoneAlarms’ Privacy Officer will provide you with the contact
information for that regulator.
Correcting/Updating Personally Identifiable Information
You are free to update or delete inaccuracies within your information at any time directly through our Site.
At
your request, ZoneAlarm will change your information; we may request evidence of your identity before doing
so.
Inasmuch as your information will never be used without your explicit consent, we are not able to update the
email
address to which you subscribe to ZoneAlarm communications on your behalf. Should you wish to update the
email
address at which you receive communications from us, please see the next section (“Updating/Unsubscribing
Your
Email Address”) below. We will respond to your access request within 30 days.
To change your information, or request that your information be changed, please use one of the following
options:
Log in "My account" section.
Send email to us at privacy_support@zonealarm.comPlease
note that this email address will reject messages with attachments of any kind.
By Postal Mail:
Attn: Privacy Contact
Zone Labs, L.L.C.
959 Skyway Road, Suite 300
San Carlos, CA 94070, USA
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.
If
you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services
contact
us at
privacy_support@zonealarm.com. We will retain and use
your
information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Updating/Unsubscribing Your Email Address
Our users are given the opportunity to “opt-out” of having their information used for purposes not directly
related to our Site at the point where we ask for the information.
If you wish to update your email address in order to receive ZoneAlarm communications at a new address, we
ask
that you unsubscribe your old email address first, and then provide your new email address by typing it into
the
“Change Registration” section of the “Registration Info” area of the “Product Info” tab in the “Overview”
pane of
your ZoneAlarm product. This will update the email address in our user communications system.
Users who no longer wish to continue receiving our communications may opt-out of receiving these
communications
in the following ways:
By clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email,
By de-selecting the “Inform me about important updates and news” option in the “Change Registration”
section
located in the “Product Information” tab of the “Overview” pane in the ZoneAlarm product,
By Postal Mail:
Attn: Unsubscribe
Zone Labs, L.L.C.
959 Skyway Road, Suite 300
San Carlos, CA 94070
